<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">

<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Cook County Board of Commissioners</origin>
        <pubdate>201711</pubdate>
        <title>Cook County 2017 Aerial Imagery Project (Contract 1590-14847), "Ground_Control_Points" for Cook County, Illinois. Vector Digital Data, Version 1.0. Published November 2017.</title>
        <edition>1.0</edition>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Chicago, Illinois</pubplace>
          <publish>Cook County Board of Commissioners</publish>
        </pubinfo>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This file is a digital geospatial Environmental Systems Research Institute (Esri) ArcGIS point feature class of the final photo-identified control points used in Cook County, Illinois. The data are stored as a point feature class in an Esri ArcGIS Version 10.3 geodatabase.

This dataset contains coordinate (x, y and z) information for a total of sixty (60) photo-identified control points throughout a project area measuring approximately 1,198 square miles. Photo-identified control points consisted of physically identifiable ground features (e.g., manholes, sidewalk intersections, etc.) and were coordinated with x, y, and z values. Photo-identified control points were located in open and flat areas (e.g., roads, clearings, etc.), and were placed/spaced consistently throughout the project area. All photo-identified control points were located on the ground (ground/orthometric elevation) and were acquired during the spring of 2017.

The horizontal positional accuracy of this dataset meets the specifications of the Federal Geodetic Control Subcommittee (FGCS) Second Order Class One (1:50000). Orthometric heights of network stations were derived from GPS heights, existing NGS benchmarks and the NGS GEOID03 model through an over-constrained least squares network adjustment. The GPS-derived orthometric heights on the project should have an accuracy of 5.0 centimeters.

This dataset is projected using the Transverse Mercator map projection. The grid coordinate system used is the Illinois State Plane Coordinate System, East Zone (Zone Number Zone 3776, FIPS 1201), NAD 83 (NSRS2007) (horizontal datum) with ground coordinates expressed in U.S. Survey Feet. The project vertical control datum was based on the NAVD88 datum.</abstract>
      <purpose>These survey points were established to provide highly accurate control points and a consistent reference network for use in the project area. They were used to assist in the creation of a series of products for Cook County that include the Digital Terrain Model (DTM) and Digital Elevation Model (DEM).

In addition, this data set was created to serve as part of a standard database for virtually all geospatial applications in Cook County, and is intended to support general location, planning, and cartography projects, as well as general inventory and asset management, Census analysis and mapping, and geocoding by address.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>201703</begdate>
          <begtime>unknown</begtime>
          <enddate>201704</enddate>
          <endtime>unknown</endtime>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.294124</westbc>
        <eastbc>-87.491292</eastbc>
        <northbc>42.178117</northbc>
        <southbc>41.441012</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>photo-identifiable ground control points</themekey>
        <themekey>survey points</themekey>
        <themekey>horizontal control points</themekey>
        <themekey>vertical control points</themekey>
        <themekey>photograph control points</themekey>
        <themekey>control network</themekey>
        <themekey>georeferencing</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Metadata Service Theme Categories</themekt>
        <themekey>Locations and geodetic networks</themekey>
        <themekey>Offline data</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1987, Codes for the Identification of the States, the District of Columbia and the Outlying Areas of The United States, and Associated Areas (FIPS 5-2): Washington, DC, National Institute of Standards and Technology.</placekt>
        <placekey>Illinois</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>Illinois Compiled Statutes, 70 ILCS 1705, State of Illinois, 1994</placekt>
        <placekey>northeastern Illinois</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>"Geographic Identification Code Scheme (PHC80-R5)." 1980 Census of Population and Housing, Bureau of the Census, U.S. Department of Commerce, April 1983.</placekt>
        <placekey>Cook County</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Chicago</placekey>
      </place>
      <temporal>
        <tempkt>none</tempkt>
        <tempkey>2017</tempkey>
      </temporal>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Access to this feature dataset is available to county and municipal agencies. Editing privileges are restricted to authorized GIS staff members or its designees.</accconst>
    <useconst>Under no circumstances may the data be redistributed or made available over a network without explicit permission from the Cook County Bureau of Technology.

It is required that the Cook County Board of Commissioners be cited in any products generated from the data. The following source citation must be included: "Source: Cook County 2017 Aerial Imagery Project (Contract No. 1590-14847), Photo-identified Control Points for Cook County, Illinois. Geodatabase Vector Digital Data, Version 1.0. Published November 2017."</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Michael J. Hammer</cntper>
          <cntorg>Cook County Bureau of Technology</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>GIS Coordinator</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>69 W. Washington Street</address>
          <address>Room 2430</address>
          <city>Chicago</city>
          <state>Illinois</state>
          <postal>60602</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>312-603-1776</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>Michael.Hammer@cookcountyil.gov</cntemail>
        <hours>09:00 - 17:00, Central Time Zone, Monday - Friday, except holidays</hours>
        <cntinst>Please contact during normal business hours.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>Photo-identified control points were provided by American Surveying &amp; Engineering, P.C. (ASE), Dixon, Illinois.</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows Vista Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.4095</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Automated processes of the vendor, coupled with repeated usage and inspection of the data have produced results (attributes) that are assessed to be highly accurate.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>This point feature class was not checked for topology.</logic>
    <complete>This dataset contains one-hundred and fifty-four (154) photo-identified ground control points that were developed for the project area. All attempts were made to ensure that photo-identified ground control points were evenly spread throughout the project area. All of these points were newly acquired ground control points for the 2017 project.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The horizontal accuracy shall be Second Order, Class II, GPS.</horizpar>
        <qhorizpa>
          <horizpav>0.01</horizpav>
          <horizpae>The GPS survey used to generate ground control points was performed to Federal Geodetic Control Subcommittee Order C1. This accuracy standard allows for a base error of 1.0 centimeter and a line-length dependent error of 10 parts per million (i.e., 1:100,000) at 95% confidence level.</horizpae>
        </qhorizpa>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>The vertical accuracy met Third Order specifications.</vertaccr>
        <qvertpa>
          <vertaccv>0.05</vertaccv>
          <vertacce>Federal Geodetic</vertacce>
        </qvertpa>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Sixty (60) photo-identifiable (PID) points were collected. The control points and checkpoints will be a surveyed, "at ground" PID feature. Features that are selected are considered semi-permanent, unambiguous and can be directly observed without an offset from the point.
Candidate features include corners of sidewalks or pads and corners of driveways (e.g., corner of walk, center of manhole lid, end of paint stripe, etc.).

The final location of the PID control and checkpoints will be selected post-imagery acquisition. This approach will mitigate
erroneous measurements during the aerotriangulation task, and increase survey efficiencines in the field.
The horizontal accuracy shall be Second Order, Class II, GPS. The vertical accuracy will meet Third Order specifications.
ASE will generate the "Control Report," which documents the results of the GPS survey. This report will include a brief
narrative of all aspects of the GPS data collection process.

Upon completion of the control point deliverables, the features were saved as an Esri version 10.3 point feature class.</procdesc>
        <srcused>FIELD_DATA_2017</srcused>
        <procdate>201711</procdate>
        <srcprod>Cook County 2017 Aerial Imagery Project (Contract No. 1590-14847), Photo-identified Control Points for Cook County, Illinois. Geodatabase Vector Digital Data, Version 1.0. Published November 2017.</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>American Surveying &amp; Engineering, P.C. (ASE)</cntorg>
              <cntper>John Dybas, PLS</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Survey Manager</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>105 West Madison Suite 1700</address>
              <city>Chicago</city>
              <state>IL</state>
              <postal>60602</postal>
              <country>U.S.A.</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>(815) 288-6231</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>j.dybas@americansurveying.com</cntemail>
            <hours>09.00 - 17.00 Central Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Business is conducted Monday through Friday, except on holidays.</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
    <cloud>0</cloud>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Cook County, Illinois</indspref>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>152</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>NAD_1983_NSRS2007_StatePlane_Illinois_East_FIPS_1201_Ft_US</mapprojn>
          <transmer>
            <sfctrmer>0.999975</sfctrmer>
            <longcm>-88.333333</longcm>
            <latprjo>36.666667</latprjo>
            <feast>984250.000000</feast>
            <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
          </transmer>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000005</absres>
            <ordres>0.000005</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>survey feet</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D_NAD_1983_NSRS2007</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
    <vertdef>
      <altsys>
        <altdatum>North American Vertical Datum of 1988</altdatum>
        <altres>0.000100</altres>
        <altunits>feet</altunits>
        <altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc>
      </altsys>
    </vertdef>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Ground_Control_Points</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Ground_Control_Points</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Merrick &amp; Company</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
    </detailed>
    <overview>
      <eaover>This dataset contains a point feature class that represents the ground control points within Cook County. Key attributes within this feature class include x and y coordinates and elevation data.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>Cook County 2017 Aerial Imagery Project (Contract No.1590-14847), Photo-identified Control Points for Cook County, Illinois. Geodatabase Vector Digital Data, Version 1.0. Published November 2017.</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>201711</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Doug Jacoby</cntper>
          <cntorg>Merrick &amp; Company</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Project Manager</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>5970 Greenwood Plaza Blvd</address>
          <city>Greenwood Village</city>
          <state>Co</state>
          <postal>80111</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>303-353-3903</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>doug.jacoby@merrick.com</cntemail>
        <hours>08:00 - 17:00, Mountain Time Zone, Monday-Friday, except holidays</hours>
        <cntinst>Please contact during normal business hours</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>This metadata file is intended to accompany the geospatial data set identified and received from Cook County. It is not to be altered or summarized. Cook County does not support secondary distribution. If this geospatial data set was received from anyone besides the Cook County Bureau of Technology, this metadata file and the geospatial data set it describes may lack integrity.</metuc>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>

